Santiago Bustamante Garcia

+57 (300) 729 6896 busta117@gmail.com skype: sbusta117 www.santiagobustamante.info

SUMMARY

I'm an engineer who love the new technologies with several years of experience developing native iOS games and applications both in academic and professional projects. I have experience developing REST APIs for communicate the client and the server. I have participated in multiple projects which gave me great experience personally and professionally working both by myself and in a team.

EXPERIENCE

iOS Developer, Null Industries

Medellín, Antioquia — jun 2015 - current

I'm a member and leader of the iOS developer team, currently i'm in charge of 1 iOS apps: PickUp (https://appsto.re/i6SD57B) and i'm working on 2 more iOS apps for Startups

iOS Developer, Periferia IT

Bogotá, Cundinamarca — apr 2014 - current

I'm a member and leader of the iOS developer team, currently i'm in charge of 3 iOS apps: weHive (https://appsto.re/i6BX8MQ) , The Squawka Football App (https://appsto.re/i6B986K) and a in-house app

iOS Developer, Rokk3r Labs

Bogotá, Cundinamarca — oct 2014 - dic 2014

I was a outsourced iOS developer, i worked in 3 iOS app for startups in USA

iOS Developer, KOGI Mobile

Medellín, Antioquia — jun 2013 - apr 2014

I was a member of the iOS developer team, in this job i was in charge of some apps and participated in the development of more than 6 apps

iOS Developer, GARA Entertainment

Medellín, Antioquia — dec 2011 - jun 2013

I developed several games using Objective-C and frameworks such as cocos2D, box2D and Unity. I developed native iOS apps and theirs backend in php and WCF. In this job I was in charge of the development of Oh My Nuts! Game(https://itun.es/i6Fk25f), their free version (https://itun.es/i6F27C2) and two other games that are not in the AppStore yet, GoBo(http://youtu.be/nGUnDZoJ_NE) and StreetRep (http://youtu.be/LWIAKDe26OM); also i developed the ipad version for a colombian retail named ÉXITO (https://itun.es/i6Fk3H9)

iOS Developer, Doctus LTDA

Medellín, Antioquia — jun 2011 - dec 2011

I developed some frameworks for use in house, also started the development of several iOS games.

iOS Developer, Freelance

I developed some iOS native apps for external clients, some of these applications still alive in the AppStore with the following links:

https://itun.es/i6FV2yH (internet radio station, Medellin Hip Hop) https://itun.es/i6Fk3H3 (sushi restaurant in Medellin-Colombia, Sushi Market)

https://itun.es/i6Fk25x (events list for ANDI)

social network using GPS called MNU, this app is not alive

TUAPP Contest 2013

I participated in the University Apps Contest powered by Cursor in Santiago de Chile, in this contest we're finalists with an application that suggests another way of tourism using quests (http://www.seekit.info/).

EDUCATION

EAFIT University (Medellin - Colombia)

System Engineering — 2007-2013

SKILLS

- Objective-C and iOS development for iOS 4.3 and above
- Swift for iOS
- Java.
- PHP.
- MySQL.
- Xcode.
- Memory management and debugging for iOS apps using instruments.
- Cocos2D, Box2D and Unity frameworks for mobile game developing.
- C#
- WCF for REST API
- Adobe products (photoshop, illustrator, flash, premiere)